

David de los Santos Cuy Sánchez

Mechatronics Engineer

Summary

I'm a Mechatronics Engineer with experience as web Full-Stack developer with expertise in many languages, frameworks and technologies like Python (Serverless Framework, azure functions, Flask), Laravel, and Angular for frontend. I implemented many Devops technologies and also I work with Docker containers. I have experience integrating software and hardware for IoT projects. I also work with electronic design, processing signals, microcontroller, linux embedded systems. My passion is about techs development and computer vision systems.

Experience

2021-Actual Application Architect, diram S.A. de C.V., San Pedro Garza García, Nuevo León.

- o Company with expertise in Electric Network Code, from electric analysis to develop product for harmonic distortion attenuation and optimizing power factor. My labor is:
 - Optimize actual cloud systems for performance and costs
 - Migrate VMs architecture to Serverless application
 - Implementing systems for continuous integration and continuous deployments.
 - Training to IT personal for software development

2020–2021 FullStack Developer Senior, Gesta Labs VG S.A.P.I. de C.V., Monterrey, Nuevo

- o An solutions for Industry 4.0 maker company, implementing digital twins, smart transport, production lines and logistics solutions.
- Projects
 - Inventory management KPIs generator and management system develop for Logistic department of Coca-Cola Femsa
 - Copilot Virtual assistant with voice recommendations develop using AI for reduce gas comsumption of trucks of Coca-Cola Femsa México (Pilot)
 - Defects Inspector An inspector and detector device of plastic injection automotive parts using computer vision algorithms with a dashboard of historic and metrics of manufactured pieces. Made for Nemak company

- 2020–2021 **Co-Founder & CTO**, Soluciones digitales para la industria y energía S.A.P.I. de C.V., Monterrey, Nuevo León.
 - Firmware development
 - Web development (Backend PHP Laravel y Frontend Angular)
 - AWS cloud architecture design
 - Web platform deployment on AWS in differents environments (Dev, Demo, Production)
 - Project description
 - AVi Energy Labs is an industrial machinery energy monitoring system on AWS platform. It use many services as [EC2, RDS, VPC, Security Groups, S3, Glue, Athena, Elasticache, SNS, SQS, etc...]
- 2017–Actual **Co-Founder & Technology director**, *Centro de Innovacion y Desarrollo Studio AV S.A.P.I. de C.V.*, Mérida, Yucatán.
 - Firmware development
 - Web development (Backend Frontend)
 - Planning and teaching workshops and courses
 - Projects
 - Decide Market Design Automated massive phone call system for public interest poll
 - Swapp Pay Automated payment and billing system for taxi drivers
 - Puntié Ballerina's movement sensor, this one was a participant in Shark Tank México TV show
 - Vinden Urban transport integral system (Passenguer counter module)
 - SWAPP Cloud Taxis management and control system (Principal view update)
 - Sinbio dispenser Level liquid meter monitoring system
 - Electronics and microcontrollers workshops and courses
 - 2016–2017 **Web Jr development**, Desarrollo de Proyectos de Ingeniería del Suereste S.A. de C.V., Mérida, Yucatán.

Actividades y proyectos:

- o Zenzzer Data analysis web page development
- UrbaTv Start-up of local server
- Vinden Passenger counter sensor development
- o Course teaching "Introducción a Raspberry pi"
- o Minis2000 Project leader of web development
- 2013 Arduino workshop teacher, Facultad de Ingeniería UADY, Mérida, Yucatán.

Education

2011–2016 **Bachelor's degree in mechatronics engineering**, *Universidad Autónoma de Yucatán*, Mérida, Yucatán, México, *Mechatronics Engineer*.

Relevant Courses

2019 Impartición de cursos de formación de capital humano de manera presencial grupal, Consejo Nacional de Normalización y Certificación de Competencias Laborales, Mérida, Yucatán, México.

Folio CONOCER: D-0005696419.

2019 Black belt, dev.f, Mérida, Yucatán, México.

Architecture design to create web applications (60 hours).

Skills

Arquiectura o AWS

Cloud

- EC2 Security Groups VNETs
- RDS
- DynamoDB
- Lambda Functions
- Glue Athena
- IoT Core IoT Greengrass IoT Analytics
- SQS SNS
- S3
- ECS ECR (Docker)

Azure

- VMs
- Database as a Service
- Azure Functions
- Lambda Functions
- Blob Storage
- Service Bus
- IoT Hub IoT Edge
- Container Regitry

Software o DevOps development

- Bitbucket pipelines
- Github Actions
- Docker
- Backend
 - PHP Laravel Framework
 - Python Serverless Framework Azure Functions Flask (API)
- Frontend
 - HTML5 CSS3 Javascript TypeScript
 - Frameworks Bootstrap JQuery Angular
- Python
 - OpenCV
 - Pandas
 - Scrapy
 - BeautifulSoup
- Database
 - SQL (MySQL)
 - NoSQL (DynamoDB)
- Others
 - C#
 - C++
 - C

Embedded o Cypress

systems o Atmel

- Espressif
- o Raspberry Pi

Languages

Spanish Native

English Intermediate

Hi. If you want to know more about my jobs, I invite you to pass for my website. If you didn't see it, don't worry, just click *here*